

DATA SCIENTIST

40 Allées de Tourny, 33000 Bordeaux, France

📕 (+33)6 16 24 58 68 | 💌 thomas.lentali@gmail.com | 🛅 thomas-lentali | 🕥 tlentali | 🖟 tlentali | 📓 tlentali

Summary.

Data Scientist with 7+ years experience specializing in machine learning across diverse fields, including personalization/recommender system, search engine relevance, bot detection, NLP, computer vision, financial fraud, gambling addiction, lifetime value prediction. My primary goal is to transform abstract knowledge into practical solutions. I'm an open-minded enthusiast who maintains expertise through helping my peers (mainly by answering questions on StackOverflow), competitions (Kaggle competition expert) and open source contributions. While passionate about data science, I also advocate Google's Machine Learning Rule #1: "Don't be afraid to launch a product without machine learning".

Work Experience ____

Betclic Group Bordeaux, France

DATA SCIENTIST

Jun. 2019 - current

- · Sport betting and casino personalization/recommender system (hybrid recommendations approaches).
- Anti Money Laundering detection (ACAMS Certified Anti-money Laundering Specialist).
- Safer gaming and addiction behavior detection (classification and time series).
- Lifetime value prediction (survival analysis).

Using: Python (Pandas, Scikit-learn, Pytorch, Tensorflow/Keras, Shap, Pytest), Apache Airflow, AWS Sagemaker, Snowflake.

Cdiscount Bordeaux, France

DATA SCIENTIST ADVISOR

Nov. 2018 - Mai, 2019

- · Massive customer clustering.
- Bot detection (pattern analysis).
- Sentiment analysis (Natural Langage Processing).
- Object detection in picture (Mask-RCNN, MSCOCO dataset).

Using: Python (Scikit-learn, Numpy, Pandas, Scipy, Shap, Luigi), SQL, Apache Hadoop Hive.

 Data Scientist
 Oct. 2016 - Oct. 2018

- Search engine relevance.
- · Products recommendation engine.
- Algorithms evaluation (A/B testing).
- Focus on website's KPI improvment.

Data Scientist Intern

Mar. 2016 - Sep. 2016

- Marketing targeting: behavioral analysis and improvement of the search engine relevance through AB test, proof of concept personnalisation client (classification and clustering).
- Geographical data: Purchase forecasting by geographic zone.
- · Statistical analysis: data enrichment with INSEE database, implementation and developement of geocoding tool.
- Intern innovation contest: Setting of a new operationnal service for the client, forcasting system of product storage to allow express delivery.

Idaia Group Bordeaux, France

Data Scientist Intern

Jun. 2015 - Aug. 2015

• Sourcing, implementation and development of machine learning tools (mainly multiclass classification) in Python and Scala into Apache Spark large-scale data framework.

Using: Python (Scikit-learn, Numpy, Scipy, NLTK), Scala, Spark (MLlib).

Education_

Msc. Applied Mathematics Bordeaux, France

BORDEAUX UNIVERSITY
Sep. 2014 - Jul. 2016

• Subjets: Optimization, operation research, machine learning, statistics, C++, Python, SQL.

Bsc. Applied Mathematics Toulon, France

TOULON UNIVERSITY Sep. 2011 - Jul. 2012

• Subjets: Statistics, probability, econometry, R, Matlab/Octave, SQL.

Bsc. Pure Mathematics Toulon, France

TOULON UNIVERSITY Sep. 2008 - Jul. 2011

• Subjets: Algebra, analysis, topology, measure theory, graph theory, C, Matlab/Octave, Wolfram Mathematica.